The Resume of

MD TAMZID HASAN

North South University Bashundhara R/A Dhaka- 1229, Bangladesh thunique1988@gmail.com +880 1711 927924

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info

Objective

To build up a career in the technical field, concentrating on research and development in order to boost production. My integrity and devotion to work motivated me to learn and share knowledge within the team, where multitasking, strong leadership, and interpersonal communication skills are most important.

Experience

Jhpiego Bangladesh
Project on Maternal Immunization Readiness Initiative.

Consultant
January 2023 to February 2024

Jhpiego Bangladesh

Develop a Health Facility Readiness Assessment Tool (HFRA)

for Maternal Immunization (MI).

Contributor

March 2023 to January 2024

Department of Public Health, North South University

Myopia and dry-eye disease among the female students of NSU.

Thesis Work November 2023

NSU Global Health Institute

People's perception, experience, and usage of health facilities.

November 2023

NSU Global Health Institute

USAID's Community-Health-Systems Strengthening Activity (CHSS).

Department of Public Health, North South University PTSD, Insomnia, and Suicidal Ideation among the firefighters of Bangladesh.

NSU Global Health Institute North South University

Department of Public Health, School of Health & Life Science North South University

Chalmers University of Technology

High Voltage Converter Transformer using Non-destructive Methods.

Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology Performance Analysis of Boost Inverter for using in PV system.

S. S. Engineering & Construction Builders, developers, & construction.

GS Engineering & Construction Bibiyana to Kaliakoir 400KV overhead transmission line supervised by PGCB. Qualitative Data Collector

Research Assistant October 2023

> Project Work September 2023

Research Assistant August 2022 to December 2023

Graduate Teaching Assistant June 2022 to January 2023

> Project Work October 2018

Thesis Work June 2018

Electrical Engineer October 2013 to July 2017

Supervision of Project April 2013 to August 2013











Portfolio: www.tamzid.info

GS Engineering & Construction Engineering & Construction

Electrical Engineer April 2013 to August 2013

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd

Designing & Installation of 10 kWp solar system with 3 hrs battery backup at MCC, Mymensingh.

Project Monitoring May 2012

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd

Installation of 2.55 kWp solar system with 4 hrs battery backup at ARC Architect, Dhaka, Bangladesh.

Project Monitoring March 2012

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd

Installation of 1.2 kWp solar system with 2 hrs battery backup at Jafrabad, Dhaka, Bangladesh.

Project Monitoring February 2012

Energy Systems (BD) Ltd Renewable energy system Assistant Engineer November 2011 to July 2012

Education

MPH in Epidemiology
Masters in EPE
Chalmers University of Technology
On hold
BSc in EEE
Ahsanullah University of Science & Technology
2021 – 2022
On hold
2006 – 2011

Honors & Scholarships

University scholarship for MPH program

International student scholarship for master's program in Sweden

Scholarship awarded to attend the study session of Peace in the Spotlight in Strasbourg, France.

Scholarship awarded to attend the project management training in the frame of Peers to Peace in Athens, Greece. North South University Adlerbert Foreign Student Hospitality Foundation

Council of Europe

Erasmus+ Scholarship

Skills

Skills are developed by professional and academic work. And good collaboration with EPI, MNC&AH, DGHS, MoHFW, Bangladesh, and other international organisations.

Research Skills

- Conduct study, proposal writing, study design, sample estimation.
- Monitoring & Evaluation the project or program.
- Grand proposal writing for the fund and development of the project.
- Transcription and translation of IDIs, KIIs, and FGDs.

Development Skills

- Develop a Health Facility Readiness Assessment Tool for Maternal Immunization in Bangladesh.
- Assist faculty members in the preparation of different module development.
- Prepare reports and design specifications, conduct research, and supervised the team.

Coordinating Skills

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info

♦ Assist faculty members with classroom instruction, exams, record keeping, and other miscellaneous projects and develop course plans.











- Assist academic staff with the development or update of learning materials, proctor exams, and record grades in the grade book.
- Survey the site and manage the design and construction of electrical systems.

Training Skills

- ♦ Tutor or mentor students in class or outside.
- Prepare reports and design specifications, conduct research, and training.
- Supervised and trained project team members.

Computer Skills

- Data analysis and visualization with R, Rstudio, and STATA.
- End Note, Zotero, and Mendely for reference management.
- ♦ MS Office (Word, Excel, and Powerpoint) & LaTEX writing tools.

Scientific Work

Journal Publication

Azaz Bin Sharif, **Md Tamzid Hasan**, Syed Sharaf Ahmed Chowdhury, and Satyajit Kundu (2023): *Inequalities in early initiation of breastfeeding in Bangladesh: An estimation of relative and absolute measures of inequality*. International Breastfeeding Journal. https://doi.org/10.1186/s13006-023-00584-y

Azaz Bin Sharif, **Md Tamzid Hasan**, Md. Habib Naziat, Tahmina Zerin, and Satyajit Kundu (2023): *Permanent, long-acting, and short-acting reversible contraceptive methods use among women in Bangladesh: An analysis of Bangladesh Demographic and Health Survey 2017-2018 data.* BMJ Open 2023;13:e073469. doi:10.1136/bmjopen-2023-073469

Md Jakaria Rahimi, **Md Tamzid Hasan**, Ripan Kumar Dhar, Md Shaheer Ibne Islam, Khatune Jannat Siddiqua, and Shahriar Azgar (2011): *Performance Analysis of Boost Inverter for Photovoltaic System*. IJETSE International Journal of Emerging Technologies in Science and Engineering, Vol.5, No.2, Dec 2011.

Skills Development Work

Training & Workshops

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info

A training on 'Mastering Monitoring, Evaluation, Accountability, Learning-Transferring Knowledge into Practice.'

DHS capacity building workshop on 'Using the DHS Dataset into Research' proposed by USAID.

A training on 'Scientific Writing' organized by School of Health & Life Science, North South University.

Workshop on 'How to develop an analytical plan for a research project- the gateway of writing a manuscript' organized by The Global Health Network Asia.

A training on 'Peace in the Spotlight' organized by SCI & VYRE.

A training on 'Project management in the frame of the Peers to Peace' co-funded by the Europe for Citizens Program of the EU.

MEAL Perspective Hub

Department of Public Health,

Global Health Institute, NSU

icddr'b

Council of Europe

SCI











Volunteering Work

Major Activities

CERIA Farm International Work Camp in Ipoh, Perak at Malaysia.

International Work Camp IN-SCI 11.10 on Achalam Eco ashram- From Ego to Eco (EE01) in Tiruvannamalai, Tamil Nadu at India.

International Work Camp NP-SCI 13.4 on Help in Reconstruction of School Building in Balthali, Panauti at Nepal.

International Work Camp BD-SCI 11.5 on Climate & Sustainable

Lifestyle with River Erosion Affected Community in Shibchar, Madaripur.

SCI Malaysia SCI India & SCI Hong Kong SCI Nepal

SCI Nepal

SCI Bangladesh

Membership

Member of Public Health Association of Bangladesh (PHAB).	2022
Member of Public Health and Science Club, North South University.	2021
Vice President of ANIMESH a social organization.	2021
Reception Host- 2018 of Chalmers Studentkårs Arbetsmarknardsdagar (CHARM),	2018
Chalmers University of Technology, Sweden.	
Member of The Institution of Engineers, Bangladesh (IEB). Memership No. M/34701.	2012
Volunteer Coordinator of Service Civil International- Bangladesh (SCI-BD).	2015
Member of Service Civil International- Bangladesh (SCI-BD).	2007

Referees

Available upon request.

Portfolio: www.tamzid.info









